Collection of salesmen's dummies, 1868-1932. Z1033.D85 A1
Lilly Library
Collection of salesmen's dummies
1868-1932
Lilly Library
Z1033.D85 A1
191 Items
A collection of books printed in the United States and England between 1868 and 1932 used for the promotion and solicitation of sales for books.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Historical Note
Salesmen's dummies (also called Salesmen's samples) are smaller representations of the finished book, containing example pages of the text and any illustrations, enclosed in a cover like the binding, plus the dust-jacket (if any). The samples were easily portable by a publisher's commercial traveller, who used it to encourage booksellers to order the book.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by author or title.
Scope and Content Note
A collection of books printed in the United States and England between 1868 and 1932 used for the promotion and solicitation of sales for books.
Related Material
Additional books from this collection are individually cataloged, and are included in Indiana University Library's online catalog (IUCAT).
Booksellers and bookselling --Colportage, subscription trade, etc.; Dummies (Bookselling) --Specimens.
- Salesmen's Dummies, 1868-1932
  - ABBOTT, JOHN S.C. and RUSSELL H. CONWELL. Lives of the Presidents of the United States of America...Portland, Maine: H. Hallett & Company, [n.d.] "Revised Edition" (Box 1, Item 1.)
  - "Abe" Lincoln's Yarns and Stories. Philadelphia: International Publishing Company, 1901. (Box 1, Item 2.)
  - AINSWORTH, WILLIAM HARRISON. Historical Romances. Philadelphia: Printed for Subscribers Only by George Barrie & Sons, n.d. "Library Edition." (Box 1, Item 3.)
  - AINSWORTH, WILLIAM HARRISON. Historical Romances. Philadelphia: Printed Only for Subscribers by George Barrie & Son, n.d. "Victorian Edition." (Box 1, Item 4.)
  - The American Nation, a History in Twenty Seven Volumes. New York and London: Harper & Brothers, [ca. 1907]. "Commonwealth Edition." (Box 1, Item 5.)
  - American Statesmen. Boston and New York: Houghton, Mifflin, [ca. 1898]. "Standard Library Edition." (Box 1, Item 6.)
  - ARMSTRONG, K.L. The International Compendium of Practical Knowledge. Chicago and Philadelphia: International Publishing Company, 1895. (Box 1, Item 7.)
  - BALZAC, HONORÉ DE. La Cornèdie humaine. Philadelphia: Printed for Subscribers Only by George Barrie & Son, [ca. 1899] (Box 1, Item 8.)
  - BALZAC, HONORÉ DE. The Édition Définitive of the Comèdie Humaine. Philadelphia: Printed for Subscribers Only by George Barrie & Son. [ca. 1898]. (Box 1, Item 9.)
  - BALZAC, HONORÉ DE. The Human Comedy. Philadelphia: Printed Only for Subscribers by George Barrie & Son, [ca. 1897]. "Edition Definitive." (Box 1, Item 10.)
  - BALZAC, HONORÉ DE. [Works]. Philadelphia: George Barrie & Son. [ca. 1897]. "Household Edition." (Box 1, Item 11.)
  - BANKS, LOUIS ALBERT. T. DeWitte Talmage His Life and Work Biographical Edition. Detroit: Bradley-Garretson Company, 1902. (Box 1, Item 12.)
  - BEAMISH, RICHARD J. The Story of Lindbergh, the Lone Eagle. Chicago: Wilmore Book and Bible Co., 1927. (Box 1, Item 13.)
  - BEATH, ROBERT B. History of the Grand Army of the Republic. Cincinnati: Jones Bros. Publishing Co.; St. Louis: The Riverside Publishing Co., 1887. (Box 1, Item 14.)
  - BEVERIDGE, ALFRED. The Life of John Marshall. Boston and New York: Houghton Mifflin, 1916. (Box 1, Item 15.)
  - [Bible]. Hurlbut's Story of the Bible, Self-Pronouncing. Philadelphia: Universal Book and Bible House, [ca. 1904]. (Box 1, Item 16.)
  - Bible Readings for the Home Circle. Mountain View, California: Pacific Press Publishing Association, 1916. (Box 1, Item 17.)
  - The Bibliophilist's Library. Philadelphia: Printed Only for Subscribers by George Barrie, n.d. (Box 1, Item 18.)
  - The Bibliophilist's Library, Second Series. Philadelphia: Printed Only for Subscribers by George Barrie, n.d. (Box 1, Item 19.)
  - BOYD, JAMES P. Life and Public Services of Hon. James G. Blaine. N.p.: Publishers' Union, 1893. (Box 1, Item 20.)
  - BURKE, EDMUND. The Writings & Speeches. Boston: Little, Brown. 1901. "Beaconsfield Edition." (Box 1, Item 21.)
  - BURROUGHS, JOHN. The Writings. Boston and New York: Houghton, Mifflin, 1905. "Riverby Edition." (Box 1, Item 22.)
  - BYRON, GEORGE GORDON. The Works. Boston: Francis A. Niccolls & Co., 1900. "Edition De Luxe." (Box 1, Item 23.)
  - BYRON, GEORGE GORDON. The Works. Boston: Francis A. Niccolls & Co., 1900. "Edition De Luxe." Variant. (Box 1, Item 24.)
  - CARLYLE, THOMAS. The Works. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1903. "Edinburgh Edition." (Box 1, Item 25.)
  - CARY, FERDINAND ELLSWORTH. The Standard Book of Knowledge. [S.l.: s.n.], 1904. (Box 1, Item 26.)
  - CLARK, JAMES HYDE. The Presidential Battle of 1896. Philadelphia: Globe Bible Publishing Co., [1896]. (Box 1, Item 27.)
  - CLAY, HENRY. The Works. New York and London: G. P. Putnam's Sons. 1904. "Federal Edition." (Box 1, Item 28.)
  - [Comédie d'Amour Series]. Paris, London and New York: Société des Beaux-Arts. 1905. "Beaux-Arts Edition." Flaubert, Dumas, Gautier, etc. (Box 1, Item 29.)
  - Courtiers and Favourites of Royalty. Paris: Societé des Bibliophiles; New York: Merrill & Baker, n.d. "Edition de Grande Luxe." (Box 1, Item 30.)
  - CRAWFORD, THERON CLARK. James G. Blaine A Study of His Life... [S.l.]: Edgewood Publishing Company, 1893. (Box 1, Item 31.)
  - CRISSEY, FORREST. Tattlings of a Retired Politician. Chicago: Clarkson & Cooper, 1904. "Special Limited Political Edition" (Box 1, Item 32.)
  - DAUDET, ALPHONSE. The Works. Boston: Little, Brown, 1898. "Limited Edition." (Box 1, Item 33.)
  - DICKENS, CHARLES. The Complete Works. New York and London: Harper & Brothers, n.d. (Box 1, Item 34.)
  - DICKENS, CHARLES. The Works. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1898. "The Complete Edition." (Box 1, Item 35.)
  - DICKENS, CHARLES. The Writings. Boston and New York: Houghton, Mifflin, [ca. 1894]. "Standard Library Edition." (Box 1, Item 36.)
  - DICKENS, CHARLES. The Writings. Boston and New York: Houghton, Mifflin, [ca. 1894]. "Standard Library Edition." Variant. (Box 1, Item 37.)
  - DICKENS, CHARLES. The Writings. Boston and New York: Houghton, Mifflin, [ca. 1894]. "Standard Library Edition." Variant. (Box 1, Item 38.)
  - DUMAS, ALEXANDRE. Celebrated Crimes. Philadelphia: George Barrie & Son, [ca. 1895]. (Box 1, Item 39.)
  - DUMAS, ALEXANDRE. Celebrated Crimes. Philadelphia: George Barrie & Son, [ca. 1895]. Variant. (Box 1, Item 40.)
  - DUMAS, ALEXANDRE. The Romances. Boston: Little, Brown, 1900. "D'Artagnan Edition." (Box 1, Item 41.)
  - EATON, WILLIAM DUNSEATH, HARRY C. READ and EDMOND McKENNA. Woodrow Wilson, His Life and Work. N.p.: Geographical Publishing Co., [ca. 1924]. (Box 2, Item 42.)
  - The Elocutionist; or, Pearls for the Speaker. Chicago: W. S. Reeve Publishing Co., [ca. 1895]. (Box 2, Item 43.)
  - EMERSON, RALPH WALDO. The Complete Works. Boston and New York: Houghton, Mifflin, 1903. "Concord Edition." (Box 2, Item 44.)
  - EMERSON, RALPH WALDO. The Complete Works. Boston and New York: Houghton, Mifflin, 1903. "Concord Edition." Variant. (Box 2, Item 45.)
  - English Ruling Cases, with American Notes. Boston: Boston Book Co., n.d. (Box 2, Item 46.)
  - EVANS, MARY ANN. The Complete Works of George Eliot. Boston and New York: Colonial Press Company, n.d. "Beacon Edition." (Box 2, Item 47.)
  - EVANS, MARY ANN. The Complete Works of George Eliot. New York: Fred DeFau & Company, n.d. (Box 2, Item 48.)
  - EVANS, MARY ANN. The Complete Works of George Eliot. New York and London: Harper & Brothers, n.d. (Box 2, Item 49.)
  - EVANS, MARY ANN. The Works of George Eliot. New York and San Francisco: Wheeler Publishing Co., [ca. 1900]. "Edition De Luxe." (Box 2, Item 50.)
  - FISKE, JOHN. The Historical Writings. Boston and New York: Houghton, Mifflin, [ca. 1902]. "Standard Library Edition." (Box 2, Item 51.)
  - FISKE, JOHN. The Historical Writings. Boston and New York: Houghton, Mifflin, [ca. 1902]. "Standard Library Edition." Variant. (Box 2, Item 52.)
  - FISKE, JOHN. The Historical Writings. Boston and New York: Houghton, Mifflin, [ca. 1902]. "Standard Library Edition." Variant. (Box 2, Item 53.)
  - Folk Stories and Fables. [Boston and New York]: Houghton Mifflin, [ca. 1907]. (Box 2, Item 54.)
  - FORD, WORTHINGTON CHAUNCEY. George Washington. New York: Goupil & Co., of Paris, and Charles Scribner's Sons, 1900. "Memorial Edition." (Box 2, Item 55.)
  - GALSWORTHY, JOHN. The Works. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons. 1912. "Manaton Edition." (Box 2, Item 56.)
  - GOETHE, JOHANN WOLFGANG VON. [Works]. Boston: Francis A. Niccolls, [ca. 1901]. "Connoisseur Edition." (Box 2, Item 57.)
  - Golden Thoughts on Mother, Home, and Heaven. Philadelphia: Bradley, Garretson & Co...., [ca. 1882]. (Box 2, Item 58.)
  - GOLDSMITH, OLIVER. The Works. New York and London: G. P. Putnam's Sons. n.d. "Turk's Head Edition." (Box 2, Item 59.)
  - GOLDSMITH, OLIVER. The Works. New York and London: G. P. Putnam's Sons, n.d. "Turk's Head Edition." Variant. (Box 2, Item 60.)
  - GOLDSMITH, OLIVER. The Works. New York and London: Harper & Brothers, 1900. "Library Edition." (Box 2, Item 61.)
  - GORDON, ANNA A. The Beautiful Life of Frances E. Willard. [S.l.]: Woman's Temperance Publishing Association, 1898. (Box 2, Item 62.)
  - The Growing World; or, Progress of Civilization. Philadelphia, Chicago and Kansas City: W. M. Patterson & Co., 1886. (Box 2, Item 63.)
  - HABBERTON, JOHN. Some Folks. New York: Derby Brothers, 1877. (Box 2, Item 64.)
  - HAIGH, HENRY A. Our Rights and Duties. Manual of Law and Business Forms, 1889. (Box 2, Item 65.)
  - HALSTEAD, MURAT. The Illustrious Life of William McKinley. [S.l: s.n.], 1901. (Box 2, Item 66.)
  - HAMILTON, ALEXANDER. The Works. New York and London: G. P. Putnam's Sons, n.d. "Constitutional Edition." (Box 2, Item 67.)
  - HANAFORD, PHEBE A. Daughters of America... Augusta, ME.: True and Company, 1882. (Box 2, Item 68.)
  - HARDY, THOMAS. [Works]. New York and London: Harper & Brothers. 1905. (Box 2, Item 69.)
  - HARTE, BRET. The Writings. Boston and New York: Houghton, Mifflin. [ca. 1896]. "Standard Library Edition." (Box 2, Item 70.)
  - HARTE, BRET. The Writings. Boston and New York: Houghton, Mifflin, [ca. 1907]. "Standard Library Edition." (Box 2, Item 71.)
  - HAWTHORNE, NATHNIEL. The Works. Boston and New York: Houghton Mifflin. 1882. "Standard Library Edition." (Box 2, Item 72.)
  - HEARN, LAFCADIO. The Writings. Boston and New York: Houghton Mifflin, 1923. "Koizumi Edition." (Box 2, Item 73.)
  - Historic Court Memoirs. Paris and Boston: Grolier Society, n.d. "Edition De Luxe." (Box 2, Item 74.)
  - History of Egypt. London: Grolier Society, [ca. 1904]. (Box 2, Item 75.)
  - History of India. London: Grolier Society, [ca. 1906]. "Baroda Edition." (Box 2, Item 76.)
  - The History of North America. Philadelphia: George Barrie & Sons, [ca. 1904]. "University Edition." (Box 2, Item 77.)
  - History of the Great Flood in Johnstown, Pa., May 31, 1889. Chicago: J. S. Oglivie, [ca. 1889]. (Box 2, Item 78.)
  - HUGO, VICTOR. The Novels. Philadelphia: George Barrie & Son, [ca. 1894]. "Edition de Bibliophile." (Box 3, Item 79.)
  - HUGO, VICTOR. The Novels. Philadelphia: George Barrie & Son. [ca. 1894]. (Box 3, Item 80.)
  - HUGO, VICTOR. The Novels. New York: Croscup & Sterling Company, 1900. (Box 3, Item 81.)
  - HUGO, VICTOR. The Works. New York: Thomas Y. Crowell. [n.d.] (Box 3, Item 82.)
  - HURLBUT, JESSE LYMAN. Hurlbut's Story of the Bible. Philadelphia: Universal Book and Bible House, 1932. (Box 3, Item 83.)
  - IBSEN, HENRIK. The (Collected) Works. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons. 1923. "Copyright Edition." (Box 3, Item 84.)
  - IBSEN, HENRIK. The Works. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons. 1911. "Viking Edition." (Box 3, Item 85.)
  - IBSEN, HENRIK. The Works. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons. 1911. "Viking Edition." Variant. (Box 3, Item 86.)
  - IBSEN, HENRIK. The Works. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons. 1911. "Viking Edition." Variant. (Box 3, Item 87.)
  - IGLEHART, FERDINAND C. Theodore Roosevelt: The Man as I Knew Him. New York: Christian Herald, 1919. (Box 3, Item 88.)
  - The Immortals [Masterpieces of French Literature]. New York and San Francisco: Wheeler Publishing Company, [ca. 1905]. (Box 1, Item 89.)
  - IRVING, WASHINGTON. The Complete Works. New York: George P. Sproul, 1899. "The Westchester Edition." (Box 3, Item 90.)
  - IRVING, WASHINGTON. The Writings. New York and London: G.P. Putnam's Sons. [n.d.] "New Sunnyside Edition." (Box 3, Item 91.)
  - JAMES, HENRY. The Novels and Tales. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1907. "New York Edition." (Box 3, Item 92.)
  - JAMES, HENRY. The Novels and Tales. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1907. (Box 3, Item 93.)
  - JAMESON, J. FRANKLIN AND J.W. BUEL. Encyclopedic Dictionary of American Reference. [S.l.: s.n.], 1901. "McKinley Memorial Edition" (Box 3, Item 94.)
  - KELSEY, D. M. Our Pioneer Heroes and Their Daring Deeds. Philadelphia and St. Louis: Scammell & Company, 1889. (Box 3, Item 95.)
  - KIPLING, RUDYARD. The Works. London and Boston: Edinburgh Society, [ca. 1899]. "Burmah Edition." (Box 3, Item 96.)
  - KIPLING, RUDYARD. The Writings in Prose and Verse. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1900. "Outward Bound Edition." (Box 3, Item 97.)
  - KIPLING, RUDYARD. The Writings in Prose and Verse. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1922. "Outward Bound Edition." (Box 3, Item 98.)
  - KOCK, CHARLES-PAUL DE. The Masterpieces. Philadelphia: Printed for Subscribers Only by George Barrie & Son, [ca. 1903]. "Edition de Luxe." (Box 3, Item 99.)
  - LEVER, CHARLES. The Novels. Boston: Little, Brown, 1895. (Box 3, Item 100.)
  - LEVER, CHARLES. The Novels. Boston: Little, Brown, 1899. "Lorrequer Edition." (Box 3, Item 101.)
  - LIVERMORE, MARY A. The Story of My Life. Hartford: A. D. Worthington & Co., 1897. (Box 3, Item 102.)
  - LOCKHART, JOHN GIBSON. Memoirs of the Life of Sir Walter Scott. Boston and New York: Houghton, Mifflin, 1901. "Large-Paper Edition." (Box 3, Item 103.)
  - LONGFELLOW, HENRY WADSWORTH. The Complete Writings. Boston and New York: Houghton, Mifflin, 1904. "Edition de Luxe." (Box 3, Item 104.)
  - LORD, JOHN. Beacon Lights of History. New York: Fords, Howard & Hulbert, [ca. 1902]. (Box 3, Item 105.)
  - LOVER, SAMUEL. The Collected Writings. Boston: Little, Brown, 1901. "Treasure Trove Edition." (Box 3, Item 106.)
  - LYTTON. EDWARD BULWER-. The Novels and Romances. Boston: Little, Brown, 1897. "Limited Edition." (Box 3, Item 107.)
  - LYTTON, EDWARD BULWER-. The Novels and Romances. Boston: Little, Brown, 1897. "Limited Edition." Variant. (Box 3, Item 108.)
  - MACAULAY, THOMAS BABINGTON. The Complete Writings. Boston and New York: Houghton, Mifflin, 1900. "Standard Library Edition." (Box 3, Item 109.)
  - MARSHALL, LOGAN. Happy Half Hours with the Bible... Philadelphia: Universal Book and Bible House, 1915. (Box 3, Item 110.)
  - MARSHALL, LOGAN. Seeing America, Including the Panama Expositions. Philadelphia: Universal Book and Bible House, [ca. 1915]. (Box 3, Item 111.)
  - MARSHALL, LOGAN. The True Story of Our National Calamity by Flood, Fire and Tornado. Philadelphia: Universal Book and Bible House, [ca. 1913]. (Box 3, Item 112.)
  - MARTIN, EDWARD WINSLOW. The History of the Grange Movement. Philadelphia, Chicago, Cincinnati, St. Louis: National Publishing Company, [ca. 1873] (Box 3, Item 113.)
  - MCCLURE, ALEXANDER K. and CHARLES MORRIS. The Authentic Life of William McKinley... Philadelphia: International Publishing Co., 1901. (Box 3, Item 114.)
  - Men and Issues of 1900. Chicago: J. S. Ziegler & Co., [1900]. (Box 3, Item 115.)
  - MEREDITH, GEORGE. The Works. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1909. "Memorial Edition." (Box 3, Item 116.)
  - MEREDITH, GEORGE. The Works. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1909. "Memorial Edition" on Japan paper. (Box 3, Item 117.)
  - MITCHELL, DONALD G. The Works of Donald G. Mitchell (Ik Marvel). New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1907. "Edgewood Edition." (Box 3, Item 118.)
  - "MOLIÈRE." The Dramatic Works. Philadelphia: George Barrie, n.d. (Box 3, Item 119.)
  - MOODY, W.R. Dwight L. Moody En biografi af hans... [S.l.: s.n., n.d.] (Box 3, Item 120.)
  - MORRIS, CHARLES. The Nations of Europe... [S.l.: s.n., n.d.] (Box 3, Item 121.)
  - MORRIS, CHARLES. The Old South and the New. Philadelphia: Universal Book and Bible House, [ca.1910?] (Box 3, Item 122.)
  - MORRIS, CHARLES. The San Francisco Calamity... Cincinnati: W.H. Ferguson Company, 1906. (Box 3, Item 123.)
  - MORRIS, CHARLES. The Standard Book of Etiquette. [S.l.]: W.E. Scull?, 1901. (Box 4, Item 124.)
  - MORRIS, CHARLES. The Volcano's Deadly Work. [S.l.: s.n.], 1902. (Box 4, Item 125.)
  - MORRISON, D.H. Songs We Love. Chicago: Dexter Supply Co., 1901. (Box 4, Item 126.)
  - MORSE, SIDNEY. Household Discoveries: An Encyclopaedia of Practical Recipes and Processes. Petersburg....: Success Company, [ca. 1914]. (Box 4, Item 127.)
  - MOTLEY, JOHN LOTHROP. The Writings. New York and London: Harper and Brothers, 1899. "Library Edition." (Box 4, Item 128.)
  - MUIR, JOHN. The Writings. Boston and New York: Houghton Mifflin, 1917. "Sierra Edition." (Box 4, Item 129.)
  - National Library Editions of Standard Sets. New York: Bigelow, Brown and Co., n.d. (Box 4, Item 130.)
  - New Library Series: American Authors. Boston and New York: Houghton, Mifflin, [ca. 1904]. (Box 4, Item 131.)
  - NORTHROP, HENRY DAVENPORT. Excelsior Writer and Speaker Being a Standard... [S.l: s.n.], 1899. (there is an ink stamp for Chicago: Northwestern Bible House) (Box 4, Item 132.)
  - NORTHROP, HENRY DAVENPORT. Jord, Hav og Himmel. N.p., [ca. 1891]. (Box 4, Item 133.)
  - Oriental Tales. London: Printed for Subscribers Only, 1901. "Limited Edition." (Box 4, Item 134.)
  - PAGE, THOMAS NELSON. The Novels, Stories, Sketches and Poems. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1906. "Plantation Edition." (Box 4, Item 135.)
  - PARKER, GILBERT. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1912. "Imperial Edition." (Box 4, Item 136.)
  - PIERCE, JAMES WILSON. Life of the Hon. James G. Blaine... Baltimore: R. H. Woodward and Company, 1893. "Authentic Edition" (Box 4, Item 137.)
  - PIERCE, JAMES WILSON. Photographic History of the World's Fair. Baltimore: R.H. Woodward & Company, 1893. (Box 4, Item 138.)
  - POE, EDGAR ALLAN. The Complete Works. Boston and New York: Colonial Press Company, n.d. (Box 4, Item 139.)
  - POE, EDGAR ALLAN. Tales and Poems. Philadelphia: George Barrie & Son, n.d. "Library Edition." (Box 4, Item 140.)
  - PRESCOTT, WILLIAM H. The Works. Philadelphia and London: J. B. Lippincott, [ca. 1904]. "Montezuma Edition." (Box 4, Item 141.)
  - PRESCOTT, WILLIAM H. [Works]. Denver: Tandy. Wheeler & Co., n.d. "Aztec Edition." (Box 4, Item 142.)
  - QUESADA, GONZALO DE. The War in Cuba ... Philadelphia: World Bible House, 1896. (Box 4, Item 143.)
  - RAMSDELL, H. J. Life and Public Services of Hon. James G. Blaine....Also, Gen. John A. Logan, by Ben Perley Poore. New York...: Standard Publishing House, 1884. (Box 4, Item 144.)
  - READE, CHARLES. [Works]. Paris and Boston: Grolier Society, n.d. "Edition de Luxe." (Box 4, Item 145.)
  - RICHARDSON, ALBERT D. A Personal History of Ulysses S. Grant... Cincinnati: Forshee & McMakin, 1885. (Box 4, Item 146.)
  - ROOSEVELT, THEODORE. [Works]. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons. 1906. "Elkhorn Edition." (Box 4, Item 147.)
  - RUSK, JOHN. The Authentic Life of T. DeWitt Talmage. N.p., [ca. 1902]. (Box 4, Item 148.)
  - RUSKIN, JOHN. The Works. London: George Allen. [ca. 1903.]. "Library Edition." (Box 4, Item 149.)
  - RUSSELL, HENRY B. An Illustrated History of Our War with Spain... Hartford, Conn.: A.S. Worthington & Co., Publishers, 1898. (Box 4, Item 150.)
  - RUSSELL, THOMAS H. Life and Work of Theodore Roosevelt. N.p., [ca. 1919]. "Memorial Edition." (Box 4, Item 151.)
  - SHIPPEN, EDWARD. Naval Battles of the World. [S.l]: James C. McCurdy, 1898. (Box 4, Item 152.)
  - SCOTT, WALTER. The Waverley Novels. New York and London: Harper & Brothers, n.d. (Box 4, Item 153.)
  - SCOTT, WALTER. The Waverley Novels. New York: Fred DeFau, n.d. (Box 4, Item 154.)
  - SCOTT, WALTER. The Waverley Novels. Boston and New York: Houghton Mifflin, 1912. "Large- Paper Edition"? (Box 4, Item 155.)
  - SHAKESPEARE, WILLIAM. The Works. Philadelphia: George Barrie, n.d. Interlinear edition on Japan paper. (Box 5, Item 159.)
  - SMITH, F. HOPKINSON. The Novels, Stories and Sketches. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1902. "Beacon Edition." (Box 5, Item 160.)
  - SMITH, F. HOPKINSON. [Novels, Novelettes, and Short Stories]. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1911. (Box 5, Item 161.)
  - STEVENSON, ROBERT LOUIS. The Novels and Tales. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1899. (Box 5, Item 162.)
  - STEVENSON, ROBERT LOUIS. The Novels and Tales. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1901. "Thistle Edition." (Box 5, Item 163.)
  - STOCKTON, FRANK R. The Novels and Stories. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1902. "Shenandoah Edition." (Box 5, Item 164.)
  - STODDARD, JOHN. L. Lectures. Boston: Balch Brothers, 1908. (Box 5, Item 165.)
  - STRICKLAND, AGNES. Lives of the Queens of England. Philadelphia: Printed for Subscriber's Only by George Barrie & Sons, [ca. 1902]. (Box 5, Item 166.)
  - TENNYSON, ALFRED. The Poetic and Dramatic Works. Boston and New York: Houghton Mifflin, 1929. "Large- Paper Edition." (Box 5, Item 167.)
  - THACKERAY, WILLIAM MAKEPEACE. [Works]. New York and London: Harper & Brothers, 1900. "Special Biographical Edition." (Box 5, Item 168.)
  - THACKERAY, WILLIAM MAKEPEACE. The Works. London: Smith, Elder: Philadelphia: J. B. Lippincott, 1901. "Charterhouse Edition." (Box 5, Item 169.)
  - THACKERAY, WILLIAM MAKEPEACE. [Works]. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1903. "Kensington Edition." (Box 5, Item 170.)
  - THACKERAY, WILLIAM MAKEPEACE. [Works]. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1903. "Kensington Edition." Variant. (Box 5, Item 171.)
  - THAYER, WILLIAM M. From Log-Cabin to the White House. Boston: James H. Earle, 1881. (Box 5, Item 172.)
  - THOREAU, HENRY DAVID. The Writings. Boston and New York: Houghton Mifflin, 1906. "Walden Edition." (Box 5, Item 173.)
  - TOLSTOY, LEO. The Works. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1900. "International Edition." (Box 5, Item 174.)
  - TOLSTOY, LEO. The Works. New York: Charles Scribuer's Sons, 1904. "International Edition." (Box 5, Item 175.)
  - TOLSTOY, LEO. The Works. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1922. (Box 5, Item 176.)
  - TROLLOPE, ANTHONY. [Works]. N.p.: Gebbie, n.d. (Box 5, Item 177.)
  - TURGENEV, IVAN. The Novels and Stories. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1903. (Box 5, Item 178.)
  - TURGENEV, IVAN. The Novels and Stories. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1904. "International Edition." (Box 5, Item 179.)
  - TURGENEV, IVAN. The Novels and Stories. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons. 1868-1932 (Box 5, Item 180.)
  - UNGER, FREDERIC WILLIAM. Russia and Japan, and a Complete History of the War in the Far East. N.p.: [W. E. Scull?, 1904?]. (Box 5, Item 181.)
  - The Universal Anthology. London: Anthological Society of London, [ca. 1899]. "Librarians' Edition." (Box 5, Item 182.)
  - The Universal Anthology. London: Clarke; New York: Merrill & Baker: Paris:Emile Terquem; Berlin: Bibliothek Verlag, [ca. 1899]. "Édition nationale." (Box 5, Item 183.)
  - Universal Manual of Ready Reference. Springfield: King-Richardson, [ca. 1905]. (Box 5, Item 184.)
  - WARD, MARY AUGUSTA [Mrs. Humphry]. The Writings. Boston and New York: Houghton Mifflin, 1911. "Westmoreland Edition." (Box 5, Item 185.)
  - WEAVER, G. S. The Lives and Graves of Our Presidents. Chicago: National Book Concern, [ca. 1883]. (Box 5, Item 186.)